TOMMY LEE

Remote Software Engineer [Full Time][Acceptable Time Zone: GMT / CST / PST]



SUMMARY

With 8 years experience for software engineering, I took the path to being a global developer focusing on new technology and innovative ideas. Now software engineering is my life and it gave me happiness that I change the world and contribute to prosperity of humanity. Leaving from financial benefit, I am glad with even only facts that my creations exist in the world and all the process for development make me to be better, more global and more kindly. My goal is to be real full stack engineer. By sharing technology, learning new tech and implementing client's idea fully, I will build my career and make the world wonderful

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Remote Full Stack Engineer

Softite LLC

- Contributed to a fleet management project that facilitates operations between fleet owner companies and maintenance companies.
- Wrote unit and end-to-end tests using Jest to ensure that the APIs are working as expected.
- Supported making the CI/CD pipeline work properly with the codebase.
- · Helped create database models, relationships, and extensions.

Senior Frontend Developer

Digital Transformation Company

1 07/2019 - 05/2020

- $oldsymbol{arphi}$ Nextbrain, United State
- Refactored legacy code while creating new features and pages using React Hooks
- Implemented workflows and guidelines for code consistency, readability, maintainability and test ability of LMS
- Used Angular 8/9 to build booking web applications with NgRX, RxJS
- Built an auction admin using Vue, Vuex, Tailwind CSS, Nuxt with firebase authentication, real time chat and user management

Field Operations Manager

United Nations Peacekeeping

1 05/2018 - 07/2019

- O.R. Congo Africa
- · Planning and execution of security escorts for UN officials.
- Assessing operational situation and presenting important updates to the senior management.
- · Upgradation and installation of internet connectivity infrastructure.
- Provision of liaison between UN and the local authorities as well as press being a public relations officer.
- Drafting detailed reports regarding daily operational situation for UNG

Project Manager

National Telecommunication Institute(NTI)

1 09/2017 - 04/2018

Quetta Pakistan

Description

- Planning and execution of multi-faceted projects that included construction, installation and maintenance of connectivity infrastructure and biometrics based identity verification and CCTV security systems.
- Developed at communication center in a newly developed remote City.
- Proposed/managed installation of media/microwave towers/satellite terminals for wireless/mobile communications.
- Ensured laying of UG and OFCC able network, installation of digital switch along with terminal electronics media.
- · Stream lined configuration of data network/OAS

LANGUAGES

English

Native ••••

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React / Redux / Next

Vue / Vuex / Nuxt

Laravel / CI

CSS / Tailwind

MongoDB / MySQL

NodeJS

Typescript / AJAX / Bootstrap

Woocommerce / Shopify

RESTful API / AWS / GIT

INDUSTRY EXPERTISE

Relationship

Partnership

REFERENCES

Johan Nilsson, CEO, Nextbrain johan.nilsson0621@wolfinc.com

Harry Piterson, CFO, Bitly

harry.piter@reilly.com

Backend Developer

Bitly

Description

- Consulted on and developed a new RESTful API as a single of truth for a host of enterprise applications used by some of the most distinguished automotive manufactures.
- Use my expertise in enterprise multi-application environments to enhance the client's development processes and improve the robustness of their applications.
- · What did you achieve in this role?

Frontend Developer

Analogfok

Web Development Company

- · Handled the heavy development of embedded JavaScript widgets on thirdparty publisher sites.
- Worked with nested frames, asynchronous loading of ads, and sizing/scaling issues for mobile and error-handling.
- What did you achieve in this role?

EDUCATION

Bachelor Degree of Computer Science